Guide to the Sarah Hoskins photographs, 2000-2014 RL.10153
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Rosenwald Schools, 2007-2014; 1; Consists of 303 computer files, approximately 10.3 gigabytes.
  - Garrard County, Kentucky, 2013-2014; 14; 31 TIFF image files, approximately 1.1 gigabytes.
    The images in this subseries document three school buildings in Garrard County, Kentucky: Scott's Fork, Garrard County, and Flatwoods. The Scott Forks school is a Rosenwald building. The Garrard County building may be. The Flatwoods building is probably not a Rosenwald. As Hoskins writes: "I was heading to Flatwoods, Kentucky as Rev. Travis and his wife Billie from Maddoxtown, KY said that he had been to preach down there and mentioned I should head over there as there was a small school behind the church. I hadn't remembered the name Flatwoods at first but once there I realized I had been there once before. Charles Hunt who was related to Georgia Blair from Sugarhill had told me that it was an old hamlet. The photos are included here from Flatwoods though I do not think it is a Rosenwald school at this point. However the other school just titled Garrard County looks very possible. The structure looks right and you can see where the windows were changed. Still need to research more. Then there is the Scott Forks School! First I could not believe the location I had never been or photographed a Rosenwald so tucked in and low. Down, down in a long valley at the base near pretty much near nothing. It seemed so out of place as did I getting there. Maybe it was the fact that it was further south then I had been since the car accident maybe the fact that the roads leading to it were insane. Maybe it was meeting a huge pickup coming out of the mud on a road on a blind curve that was barely a lane next to a creek. I visualized the dully truck the rebel flag waving running me off and into the creek. A lone cow in the middle of the road around a bend. You get the idea. Then as the road ends and T's. There it sits. I don't know that I have ever been as stunned to see a Rosenwald school, still there, still standing in a valley so low I didn't know that we would get out of there alive. Not to mention the Pit Bull and the gun shots from the inside of the school, but what a reward finding it. I have also included some of the roads leading to the school. How can you not include a lane called Sad Lane."
    - Flatwoods School, 2013
      Was all black community at one time. Confirmed building was a school it is behind church which was also common.
    - Garrard County, 2013
    - Flatwoods Outhouse, 2013
    - Flatwoods School, 2013
    - Garrard County, 2013
    - Flatwoods School, 2013
    - Flatwoods School, 2013
    - Garrard County, 2013
    - Flatwoods School, 2013
    - Flatwoods School, 2013
    - Flatwoods School, 2014
    - Flatwoods Outhouse, 2013
    - Flatwoods School, 2013
    - Scott's Fork Rosenwald School, 2014
      Bullet Holes coming out of window.
    - Road in to Scott's Fork Rosenwald School, 2013
    - Scott's Fork Rosenwald School, 2013
    - Scott's Fork Rosenwald School, 2013
    - Scott's Fork Rosenwald School, 2013
    - One of the roads leading to the Scott's Fork Rosenwald School, 2013
    - Other road out of Scott's Fork Rosenwald School, 2013
    - One of the "roads" leading to the Scott's Fork Rosenwald school, 2013
    - Scott's Fork Rosenwald School, 2013
    - On the way to Scott's Fork School, 2013
    - Scott's Fork Rosenwald School, 2013
    - Flatwoods School, 2013
    - Flatwoods School, 2013
    - Scott's Fork Rosenwald School, 2013
    - Scott's Fork Rosenwald School, 2013
    - Scott's Fork Rosenwald School, 2013
    - Scott's Fork Rosenwald School, 2013
    - Scott's Fork Rosenwald School, 2014
  - Hootentown, Kentucky, 2012; 16; 7 TIFF image files, approximately 0.2 gigabytes.
    The images in this subseries document the Jouett's Creek Rosenwald school in Hootentown, Kentucky. Hoskins writes: "When I first went to Hootentown back in 2003 to try and locate this black hamlet I learned about the church and school. My friend Betty Smithers from the hamlet of Jonestown was with me. We saw the sign marked Hootentown Lane, but the turn and lane where so tight and straight up we had to turn around and come back at it. We then realized it was too steep to come in that way and had to turn around again. Finally we headed up and in. There was a split as you drove up the lane and we took the one to the right. It dead ended at the top of the hill. Two large big burly white men, an older woman and a middle age woman and two kids were there. We were pretty much stuck as the road ended into their trailer. Betty rolls down the window and says," We're here looking for the black hamlets. " I figured this was it, the guns were being loaded. Then the middle aged woman named Cheryl Bryant says, "well honey I am the blackest thing out here come on out." She said we were lucky we didn't take the other lane or he would have started shooting. She showed us how to locate old grave stones by looking for honey suckle plants. We found some from the old hamlet and then she told us about the church down below. " I sometimes go sit behind my trailer on the side of the hill and listen to them singing on Sunday." She pointed the way and told us how to go out and quickly turn left. That is how I first came to this school. We had completely missed the lane to the church. We found our way into the lane and over the single lane bridge that led to the church. I held my breath as we crossed over it hoping we would make it to the other side. I felt sure I felt it sway. We pulled into and onto the gravel and there was a car parked. It was a Saturday. I walked up and could hear a vacuum cleaner running and knocked. That was how I met Bobby Hart. He showed us in and around and when I asked about the small building behind the church he said, "It was an old school, someone from Sears built it." I have spoken with the Rosenwald Foundation and they feel it is the Jouett's Creek school. The photos match up, it had been listed in the wrong location. As of 2012 there is a sign that says Jouett's Creek Lane up the road, which helps confirm it is correct. I am sure this is right.
    - Jouett's Creek School, 2011
    - Jouett's Creek School, 2011
    - Jouett's Creek School, 2011
    - Jouett's Creek School, 2011
    - Jouett's Creek School, 2011
    - Jouett's Creek School, 2011
    - Road into Jouett's Creek School, 2011
  - Nicholasville, Kentucky, 2012-2014; 25; 16 TIFF image files, approximately 0.6 gigabytes.
    The images in this subseries document the Nicholasville Colored School (also known as Rosenwald Dunbar High) in Nicholasville, Kentucky. Hoskins writes: This is now an apartment building with at least 9 different apartments. You can see on some of the detail shots how the facade has changed and windows have been bricked over. Tribly and Charles Railey were both students at the Rosenwald School,l they have lived here all their lives. Tribly used to live across the street but her memory is slipping so she now lives with her brother Charles. About five or six years before these images were made my friend Don Moore brought me out here to show me the school. His wife Gladys Moore had gone to the Cadentown Rosenwald school and he knew I would be interested.I mention all of this because when Don and I were out taking pictures back around 2005 Charles opened his door to see what I was doing but when I asked could I take his picture he said no and went back inside. His house is two away from the school. Fast forward to 20012 my daughter Emma and I are out front taking pictures of the school and Charles opened up the door and beginning waving at me say, "I remember you, you were here before taking pictures before." and waves me right on in his house. It was a happy surprise, I kind of wonder if he was worried about us as much of the neighborhood had fallen on a bit of hard times and there were some guys across the street who were a bit intimidating not to mention more than a bit drunk. For whatever reason it was a welcome surprise to be welcomed into their home. They talked and shared stories of the school and offered us candy. We were able to leave them with a bunch of Butterscotch brownies that Emma had made. Good people a good visit."
    - Nicholasville Colored School (Rosenwald Dunbar High), 2014
    - Tribly Railey in the home she shares now with her brother Charles, 2013
      They both went to the Nicolasville Colored School, which is just a few doors down. She now is loosing her memory so moved in with her brother. She used to live across the street.
    - Charles and Tribly Railey, 2012
      Brother in sister outside the home they share and in fron to the.Nicolasville Colored School.
    - Charles and Tribly Railey, 2012
    - Charles and Tribly Railey, 2014
    - Charles and Tribly Railey, 2014
    - Charles and Tribly Railey, 2014
    - Nicholasville Colored School (Rosenwald Dunbar High), 2012
    - Triby Railey and Charles Railey playing dominos in their home next to Rosenwald school where they went, 2012
      They are brother and sister and in lived on this road their whole lives.
    - Nicholasville Colored School (Rosenwald Dunbar High), 2012
    - Nicholasville Colored School (Rosenwald Dunbar High), 2014
    - Nicholasville Colored School (Rosenwald Dunbar High), now apartments, 2014
    - Nicholasville Colored School (Rosenwald Dunbar High), 2012
    - Nicholasville Colored School (Rosenwald Dunbar High), now apartments, 2012
      Woman coming out to check on me.
    - Nicholasville Colored School (Rosenwald Dunbar High), now apartments, 2012
    - Triby Railey and Charles Railey playing dominos in thier home next to Rosenwald school where they went., 2012
  - New Castle, Kentucky, 2012; 24; 3 TIFF image files, approximately 0.1 gigabytes.
    The images in this subseries document the Rosenwald school building in New Castle. At the time this photograph was taken, it was used as a home.
    - New Castle Rosenwald School, 2012
    - Rosenwald School now a home, 2012
    - New Castle Rosenwald now a home, 2012
  - Warsaw, Kentucky, 2012-2014; 29; 3 TIFF image files, approximately 0.1 gigabytes.
    The images in this subseries document school buildings in Warsaw and Eminence, Kentucky. Of Warsaw, Hoskins writes: "We had driven into Warsaw as Pastor Travis was from the area and we were exploring. I happen to see an African American man and got out of the car and asked him if her knew of any old black schools. He told me how to get to the Warsaw school which was where he went. He gave me directions which led me to this school.Itl is not listed in any records I have found but I am sure it is correct because of how it looks." Of Eminence, she writes: "Emma and I drove down a dead end road and saw this older African American lady and her son on their front porch. Over the years I have learned if you can find someone of a certain age who is black they will know about the schools. That is why I asked them. She said there was an old black school and offered to show us. They got off their front porch and into a car and said to follow them which we did. It wasn't far but is was passed a closed and posted no trespassing sign and dilapidated building. Then through an opening of some trees. It was by no means a road. I began to wonder what we were doing. We got out and there didn't seem to be anyone home. We were greeted by many No Trespassing Signs and dog warnings. I took a quick photo. The mother and son were very kind and they told us we should really be careful and not so trusting of people. Which was funny as it was crazy where we had just followed them to. They worried about us and asked if we wanted them to take us back to the highway. We thanked them and headed on our way. Pretty sure this is a school and it was indeed an adventure. It is hard to tell by this photo but there was one in Eminence, Kentucky Henry County which is where this was and it is listed on this street. However you won't know it was a street anymore because it is actually behind the street and through the trees."
    - Eminence School building, 2012
      Not sure.Was brought here by an older lady who went here. She said it was a Rosenwald. Hard to tell if it was one but there was one in Eminence, Kentucky Henry County which is where this was.
    - Warsaw School, 2014
    - Warsaw School, 2012
  - Zion Hill, Kentucky, 2012-2014; 32; 8 TIFF files, approximately 0.3 gigabytes.
    The images in this subseries document former students of the Zion Hill Rosenwald school. Hoksins writes: "I have included images here of some former Rosenwald students from Zion Hill. We got everyone together for a group photo for a piece I was doing for Preservation magazine in front to the historic marker that references the Rosenwald school that used to be there. It ended up being a truly special day as some of the students hadn't seen each other in years. Zion Hill has worked extremely hard to have their community recognized. It is also one of the communities I have been photographing for years for The Homeplace project."
    - Rev. Roger Raglin receives a hug from Georgia Howard, both former students, 2012
    - Former Rosenwald students from Zion Hill in front of historic marker, 2014
      L-R Cad Mulder, Robert Raglin, Louise Raglin, Georgia Howard, Earl Raglin, Merytle B. Hughes.
    - Rev. Earl Raglin.hugs another former Rosenwald student Georgia Howard in front of the historic marker honoring the school, 2012
      Louise Ragain in background.
    - Former Rosenwald students from Zion Hill in front of historic marker, 2014
      L-R Cad Mulder, Robert Raglin, Louise Raglin, Georgia Howard, Earl Raglin, Merytle B. Hughes
    - Myrtle B. Hughes, former Rosenwald school student in front of historc marker for Rosenwald school, 2012
      She is known for her homemade rolls which she is holding here. She is one of the best cooks there.
    - Myrtle B. Hughes, former Rosenwald school student in front of historc marker for Rosenwald school, 2012
    - Myrtle B. Hughes, former Rosenwald school student in front of historc marker for Rosenwald school, 2012
    - Myrtle B. Hughes, former Rosenwald school student in front of historc marker for Rosenwald school, 2012
  - Browntown, North Carolina, 2007-2014; 4; 6 TIFF image files, approximately 0.2 gigabytes.
    The images in this subseries document the Rosenwald school building in Browntown (now Scott's Hill), North Carolina. Hoskins writes: "This school was pretty easy to find sitting next to the side of a busy road. One of those roads that is leading you into 'vacationland' as I sometimes call it. My family vacations have a tendency to end on a quest for Rosenwald schools. I kind of smile as I write this thinking of all the over-priced nick nacks inside and wondering if they knew the value of the beautiful sign on the front of their building. I asked the building and they said it had been a school once but needless to say their interest in the building didn't seem too deep and I didn't feel like I should press it. It was a good thing we found this one as the next attempt ended up with a 150 mile side trip to a vacant lot."
    - Browntown Rosenwald School, Scotts Hill NC, 2010
      Now an antique/gift store.
    - Browntown Rosenwald School, Scotts Hill NC, 2010
    - Browntown Rosenwald School, Scotts Hill NC, 2010
    - Browntown Rosenwald School, Scotts Hill NC, 2014
    - Browntown Rosenwald School, Scotts Hill NC, 2010
    - Browntown Rosenwald School, Scotts Hill NC, 2010
  - Dunn, North Carolina, 2010-2014; 10; 6 TIFF image files, approximately 0.2 gigabytes.
    The images in this subseries document the Rosenwald building that formerly housed the Harnett County Training School, later Harnett High School.
    - Harnett County Training School, 2012
    - Harnett County Training School, 2012
    - Harnett County Training School, 2012
    - Harnett County Training School, 2012
    - Harnett County Training School, 2012
    - Harnett County Training School, 2014
  - Greenevers, North Carolina, 2012; 15; 5 TIFF image files, approximately 0.2 gigabytes.
    The images in this subseries document the Little Creek Rosenwald school building, as well as two men working on converting the building into a community center.
    - Little Creek Rosenwald School, 2012
      Working on for a new Community Center.
    - Little Creek Rosenwald School, 2012
    - Little Creek Rosenwald School, 2012
      These two men were working on school.
    - Little Creek Rosenwald School, 2012
    - Little Creek Rosenwald School, 2012
  - Johnston County, North Carolina, 2012; 17; 23 TIFF image files, approximately 0.8 gigabytes.
    The images in this subseries document the interior of the Princeton Graded School Rosenwald building.
    - Princeton Graded School, 2012
    - Princeton Graded School, 2012
    - Princeton Graded School, 2012
    - Princeton Graded School, 2012
    - Princeton Graded School, 2012
    - Princeton Graded School, 2012
    - Princeton Graded School, 2012
    - Princeton Graded School, 2012
    - Princeton Graded School, 2012
    - Princeton Graded School, 2012
      The white brick was added on later to the original Rosenwald school.
    - Princeton Graded School, 2012
    - Princeton Graded School, 2012
    - Princeton Graded School, 2012
    - Princeton Graded School, 2012
    - Princeton Graded School, 2012
    - Princeton Graded School, 2012
    - Princeton Graded School, 2012
    - Princeton Graded School, 2012
    - Princeton Graded School, 2012
    - Princeton Graded School, 2012
    - Princeton Graded School, 2012
    - Princeton Graded School, 2012
    - Princeton Graded School, 2012
  - Magnolia, North Carolina, 2012; 20; 1 TIFF file, approximately 0.1 gigabytes.
    The image in this subseries documents the Stanford Rosenwald school building.
    - Stanford School, 2012
  - Pender County, North Carolina, 2010; 26; 4 TIFF image files, approximately 0.1 gigabytes.
    The images in this subseries document the Currie Rosenwald school building.
    - Currie Rosenwald School, 2010
    - Currie Rosenwald School, 2010
    - Currie Rosenwald School, 2010
    - Currie Rosenwald School, 2010
  - Winston-Salem, North Carolina, 2012; 30; 2 TIFF image files, approximately 0.1 gigabytes.
    The images in this subseries document the former Atkins High School building, built with financial assistance from the Rosenwald fund.
    - Atkins (Former High School), 2012
    - Atkins (Former High School), 2012
  - Wise, North Carolina, 2013; 31; 11 TIFF image files, approximately 0.4 gigabytes.
    The images in this subseries document the Rosenwald school builidng In Wise, North Carolina. Hoskins writes: "There are several reasons I am convinced this is a Rosenwald school. The first and what might seem the strangest is the comment I received as I stepped out of my car with my camera in hand. There was a large white man standing with a chain saw who looked more than a bit intimidating. I asked if it was OK to take a photo of the building. "Yes, it is an old white school. " I think it was the fact that he made such a point to say it was white school that really led me to believe it was a Rosenwald school for black children. We wandered around and he came over and told us (my daughter and I) that he owned the school and allowed us inside to make photos. There were signs saying Ruritan Club which I had never heard of at the time,however I have seen them more frequently now in the south. The wood and windows looked right for a Rosenwald as did the cloak room. Over the years that is one thing that many of the elders who went to the schools is the cloak rooms. This one had one as well and truly matched up."
    - Building in Wise, NC, 2013
    - Building in Wise, NC, 2013
    - Interior of building in Wise, NC, 2013
    - Interior of building in Wise, NC, 2013
    - Building in Wise, NC, 2013
    - Building in Wise, NC, 2013
    - Building in Wise, NC, 2013
    - Building in Wise, NC, 2013
    - Cloakroom of building in Wise, NC, 2013
      One of things that those who went to Rosenwald schools always mentioned was a cloak room. Which leads me to believe even more that this was and is a Rosenwald school.
    - Interior of building in Wise, NC, 2013
      Window
    - Building in Wise, NC, 2013